KOWSHIK VARMA



Devops Engineer

Address Bengaluru, KA, 560035

Phone +91 9176559383

E-mail kowshikvarmag@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kowshik-varma-gadhiraju

Experienced Devops and QA Engineer with over 7+ years of experience in Networking. Good reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in field of work. And have a Good working knowledge in cloud and devops environment. Have completed Aws Certification.



Skills

- Security testing
- Networking Devices Firewalls , Switch , Router ,Load Balancer
- Scripting Python
- Framework Pyats and Robot framework
- Cloud-AWS(EC2,VPC,S3,EFS,Cloud Front..etc) Azure(Creation of virtual machines)
- Containerization & Orchestration tools : Docker and Docker Swarm.
- Code Versioning Tools- Github and bitbucket
- CI tool Jenkins and Project Management tools Jira ,Confluence
- ◆ Infrastructure as Code using Cloud Native tools Multi cloud automation tool Terraform
- Configuration Management tool Working Knowledge on Ansible
- Virtualization tools vSphere , Oracle Virtual Box and Hyper-V
- Operating System Windows, Linux (Ubuntu, Centos, Redhat, Freebsd, Kali)

Work History



Devops & QA Engineer

Wipro Technologies Ltd, Bangalore, Karnataka

Period: May2019-Present

Responsibilities:

- Used Git for source code version control and integrated with Jenkins for CI/CD pipeline.
- Experience in building CI/CD pipeline automation in tools like Jenkins with scripting languages like groovy
- Working with team members in configuring new setups like Apache, OCSP and multi- host server and required server setups on AWS cloud using VPC in a public and private subnets accordingly.
- Configuring the Docker containers by using Docker Images and customization of images using Docker file and maintaining them in Docker registries.
- Configured AWS Virtual Private Cloud with public and private subnets, Routing Tables, Internet Gateway, Network Access Control Lists and Security groups appropriately for internet facing web servers.
- Extensively used Ansible ad-hoc commands instead of using ansible playbooks for each and every small task in ansible.
- Understanding on new feature TLS1.3, design and develop test plans for the same.
- Working on Customer filed defects and automating them using robot framework.
- Automating the manually written testcases using pyats framework and Integrating those scripts for performing regression runs.
- Working on Integrated Service Engine to perform various test in it according to ISE version and patch release.

Lead Engineer

HCL Technologies Ltd, Chennai, TamilNadu

Period: Mar2017-May2019

Responsibilities:

- · Automated the manual test cases and performed manual testing for new features.
- Experience in testing firepower devices like FP2120,4110,9300 series with various protocols.
- · Analyzing and fixing the script enhancement and behavior changes using pyats framework for the bugs raised by regression team.
- · Setup the testbed using Quali Systems(cloud) for managing of devices at various location.
- \cdot Common libraries used by test cases are fixed using GIT by cloning all files related to script to local database, make necessary changes and push to GIT repository.
- · Worked on dev test modules like high availability and automated SDT.
- · Vulnerability testing is done for every customer release build in firepower device

Network Engineer

Yalamanchili Software, Chennai, TamilNadu

Project - Network Security Engineer -YALAMANCHILI SOFTWARE EXPORTS LTD.

Period: Mar2016-Jan2017

Responsibilities:

- · Performed regular maintenance on the network devices at data center to ensure issues were resolved quickly and never interfered with regular operations.
- \cdot Implementing traffic filters using Standard and Extended access-lists in Fortigate 100D and Cisco ASA 5520 Firewalls for infrastructure.
- · Configuring and Troubleshooting VPN along with client network team on watchguard device for any issues.
- · Configuring F5 load balancer for accessing web pages inside web and app server based on rules set and load balancing traffic between servers.
- · Coordinating with service Provider for any route refresh or BGP link down and providing them with all troubleshooting output to get the reason for the outage(RFO).

System Engineer

Precision Techserve(CTS), Chennai, TamilNadu

Project – System Engineer – Precision tech serve (Cognizant solutions).

Period: Jan2014-March2016

Responsibilities:

- Installing and configuring Cisco IOS on routers based on existing project documentation & run book in routers.
- Maintain the SLA time and troubleshoot the issue within it based on tickets raised for incidents.
- Troubleshooting tickets as usual operations raised by customer for any network related issues in existing connections.
- Troubleshooting Juniper EX2200 and Cisco 2960X switches.
- Provide Support to L3 Team for any outage within our infrastructure with some basic Troubleshooting steps.
- Security administration port security on switch & Mac binding.

প্র

Education

Aug 2009 Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science

Sep 2013 Alpha College Of Engineering. - Chennai

Mar 2008 HSC: Computer Science

St.johns.Matriculation Higher Secondary School - Chennai

Mar 2009 Completed my HSC 12th standard

Mar 2006 - SSLC: Computer Science

Apr 2007 St.johns Matriculation Higher Secondary School - Chennai Completed my SSLC 10th standard



Affiliations

- Conducted an Event "Hacker Hunt" at college symposium.
- Participated in Zonal level 100m run in Anna university.
- Awarded Best performer for the quarter at HCL.



Certifications

Sep 2013 Cisco Certified Network Associate(CCNA)

Jan 2021 Aws Certified Cloud Practitioner(AWS-CCP)